so now that we have seen a two level
page table let's see if we can work with
a four level page table
this time let's assume we have a 64-bit
virtual address space a 64 kilobyte page
size
an 8 byte page table entry and we have a
relatively large program that is only
using addresses zero through four
gigabytes from this huge address space
the flat page table size is very large
the question for you is it's a power of
two what power of two so it's 2 to what
and if you have a four level page table
where the page number is split equally
so the bits of the page number are
divided into four equal groups to access
these page tables this page table uses
how many kilobytes of memory